<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chafouin</title>
    <link>https://chafou.in/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chafouin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 22:41:56 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chafou.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS AutoScaling Group &amp; lifecycle hook</title>
      <link>https://chafou.in/posts/aws-asg-lifecycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 22:41:56 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chafou.in/posts/aws-asg-lifecycle/</guid>
      <description>AWS AutoScaling Group lifecycle management AutoScaling Service Amazon Web Services AutoScaling is a service that automatically adjust the capacity of a group of EC2 instancesd. It is possible to set a fixed number of instance or set rules so the group will scale according to a metric. An AutoScaling Group is a group of instance launched by the AutoScaling service on your behalf, using a Launch Configuration or a Launch Template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS AutoScaling Group &amp; dynamic Route53 records</title>
      <link>https://chafou.in/posts/aws-asg-ddns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 11:32:20 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chafou.in/posts/aws-asg-ddns/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic DNS for AWS AutoScaling Group AutoScaling group and Route53 record When you are deploying your application on AWS, you might want to use an AutoScaling Group to launch your EC2 instances. It groups logically the instance and has a lot of feature such as auto healing, scalability according to metrics, load balancer integration, etc. A good ptractice is to always run your instance in such group. Everything seems great with AutoScaling Group, except when you want to have a DNS record pointing on your instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KVM &amp; Dynamic DNS: dynamic virtual machine naming</title>
      <link>https://chafou.in/posts/kvm-ddns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 15:32:15 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chafou.in/posts/kvm-ddns/</guid>
      <description>In my previous article, we saw how to provision KVM virtual machine with PXE. We have our own virtual machine deployment lab in our own laptop. And that&amp;rsquo;s great. Each time we create a virtual machine, we need to connect with Spice in order to get the private IP or use tool like nmap or check the ARP cache. If you need to deploy a lot of virtual machine, this will become a real hassle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KVM &amp; PXE: virtual machine setup automation</title>
      <link>https://chafou.in/posts/kvm-pxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 19:55:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chafou.in/posts/kvm-pxe/</guid>
      <description>What is virtualization ? Since the 1960s and mainframe computers, computer scientists have made huge progress on virtualization. However until late 1990s, this was out of fashion. Popek and Goldberg defined it as &amp;ldquo;an efficient and isolated duplicate of a real machine&amp;rdquo;. Nowadays, even if some are still reluctant to the idea, virtual machines are present everywhere in the IT world. Their purposes are various: development environment, production isolation, testing bed, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>